

CONTACT

Address: Paris, France

Email: cochenercamille@yahoo.fr

Tel: (+33) 06 71 46 78 07 Github: camillecochener LinkedIn: camillecochener

Website: camillecochener.github.io

Availability: Immediate

SKILLS

Machine Learning & Deep Learning

Statistics

Data Analysis

Data Visualization

Data Engineering

GCP, AWS

R, Python, Java, Scala Programming

Numpy, Pandas, Scikit-learn

SQL, NoSQL

Hadoop, Spark

Keras, TensorFlow API, PyTorch

Git, Linux, MacOS, Docker, MLFlow

Curious

Team player

Problem solving

Adaptability

Oral & written communication

LANGUAGES

- French (Native)
- English (Fluent)

PERSONAL DEVELOPMENT

Coursera Certificates:

- Deep Learning (CNN, Sequence Models, GAN) by deeplearning.ai
- Al for Medicine by deeplearning.ai
- Data Science Specialization by John Hopkins University

Meet-up:

• Speaker (Paris Data Ladies, 2020 december edition on Computer Vision, 100 Data experts attended)

HOBBIES

Sports:

- Horse riding
- Yoga
- Fitness
- Tennis
- Baking Piano Watercolour

Others:

Travel

CAMILLE COCHENER

I am now available for a Data Scientist position.

Data Scientist

Data Scientist with a Post Master's Degree in Data Science and Big Data from Télécom Paris, with more than 3 years experience in consulting in Statistics, Data Analytics and Machine Learning. Three words to define myself: passionate, efficient and eager to share.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

07/2020 -**DATA SCIENTIST - COMPUTER VISION**

01/2021 **LIXO -** Startup created at the end of 2019 - 5 employees

6 months In charge of the AI module of the Lixo solution.

- Trained Deep Learning models using Python, Tensorflow, GCP from notebooks to deployment
- Miniaturized and tested neural networks on an embedded system
- Participated in bringing the models into production on the client's site
- Wrote scientific documents to obtain funding

Results: Performance of the model +120%, deployed in production, +90K€ grant earned

01/2017 -07/2019 2 years,

7 months

ESSILOR

lixo

DATA SCIENTIST CONSULTANT

Consulting company: IT&M STATS (IT&M group)

Neuilly-sur-Seine, France

Agoranov, Paris, France

► ESSILOR INTERNATIONAL, R&D. Créteil, France (10 months)

Led the 1st Data Science project related to the analysis of the data collected during the development of anti-reflective products to optimise Time To Market.

- Mapped processes and carried out an inventory of available data
- Structured data using data manipulation techniques
- Identified value-added topics and proposed appropriate statistical methods
- Performed analysis/visualisations and built Machine Learning models using Python, SQL, R
- Trained internal teams in data science methods and programming

Results: Delivered an analytical report with relevant insights, identified areas of improvement reorienting the data-driven strategy of the anti-reflective R&D department

► L'ORÉAL R&I, Chevilly-Larue, France (1 year, 6 months)

In charge of Data Science projects within the Scientific Computing team in line with the activities of the laboratories and product performance evaluation services.

ĽORÉAL

- Understood business needs through communication with product experts
- Structured, cleansed and explored the data
- Carried out and implement statistical analysis and adapted Machine Learning models using R
- Developed applications for the routine analysis of laboratories

Results: Deployment of 2 applications, +15 analysis and models delivered to laboratories.



► INTERNAL DIVISION IT&M STATS, Neuilly-sur-Seine, France (2 years, 7 months)

- In charge of fixed-price projects and programming and Machine Learning trainings. • Mutuelle Chorum: Segmented a customer portfolio and predicted an appetence score
- Clarins Laboratories: Built a classification model to classify skin pores
- Société Générale: Trained a team of 5 Data Analysts on R packages during 2 days

03/2016 -09/2016

DATA SCIENTIST INTERN

Clarins Laboratories 6 months

Pontoise France

Modeled the relationships between consumer perceptions and instrumental measurements of skin mechanical properties in order to drive the development of the new products.

EDUCATION

2019 -2020

▶ <u>Télécom Paris</u> - Post Master's Degree in Data Science & Big Data

Topics: Statistics, Machine Learning (supervised, unsupervised, Deep Learning...), Data Engineering (NoSQL, distributed systems, cloud storage and computing...), Data Visualization

2013 -2016

▶ Agrocampus Ouest - Engineer (Master's Degree), Data Science Specialization

Topics: Statistics, Data Management, Factorial Analysis, Data Analysis applied to biological, marketing and agronomic data, Machine Learning (supervised, unsupervised), Programming

2010 -2013

▶ Lycée Chaptal (Paris) - Preparatory school to enter the French Grandes Ecoles

DATA SCIENCE / DATA ENGINEERING PROJECTS

2019 -2020

Carrefour-X AI & Retail Challenge - Rang 1/26: designed a local Marketing Mix Modeling analysis and prediction of the impact of marketing media levers on sales (ROI) - 2 months Tech: GCP, Big Query, Python, CatBoost, Dash, Shap, MMM

- Bike Sharing Predictions: predicted the number of bikes shared at a London bike station Tech: Python, Spark, Open data, Random Forests, Validation croisée
- GDELT: built a fast and resilient ETL to analyze GDELT data (2.5 TB) Tech: Cassandra, Spark, AWS, Zeppelin, ETL
- Kaggle Toxic Comment Classification: built a multi-label model to predict the toxicity of a comment using textual data from Wikipedia Tech: Deep Learning, NLP, Keras, Dash

AWARDS

Laureate "Trophée Syntec": competition that rewards the best quantitative studies 2016 <u>Travel Award</u> obtained for speaking at the SPISE congress in Vietnam